Senior Software Engineer with 13 years of experience, specializing in backend development using Java, and front end with Angular and Ionic. Experienced with all stages of the software development life cycle (SDLC), various CI/CD systems and build tools (ant, maven, gradle, etc.), software development, RESTful web services, OAuth2, agile methodologies and the main web development frameworks such as Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA. With knowledge in database technologies such as MySQL, Oracle or PostgreSQL, also in non-relational databases such as MongoDB, Neo4J, Cassandra. Strong background in programming HTML, CSS, TypeScript, experience working with XML, XSLT, XPath, JSON, serverless technologies, Amazon Web Services (AWS), familiar with Git, Jenkins, BitBucket, project management, scrum and customer relations. Strong interpersonal and communication skills, self-motivated with a positive attitude.

WESCLEY DE MACÊDO SOUSA



+351 912 381 330



wescleysrn@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/wescle y-sousa/



https://github.com/wescleysrn

Skill Highlights

- Software Development
- Agile Methodologies
- AWS Development
- Back-End Web Development
- Complex problem solver
- Java
- Angular
- Postgres
- Oracle
- MySQL
- Spring
- REST
- Leadership
- Innovative
- Service-focused

Experience

09/2012 to now

Senior Consultant Engineer: Capgemini, Portugal

- Fullstack software engineer, working on the Merchant Portal project for the French group Natixis.
- Responsible for defining Angular architecture for the project using the group's design system and adapting it in a modular and responsive way.
- Responsible for defining a new architecture for the Spring Batch project and implementing batches for processing and ingesting data, using multi thread resources.
- API creation work using the spring framework and preparation of SQL DDL and DML scripts for execution in the Oracle database.

03/2020 to 08/2022

Technical Coordinator Data Intelligence Nucleus: Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Supply, Brazil

- Technical Coordinator at the Data Intelligence Nucleus, structure activities to work with data sharing, contracting a cloud service, defining the on-premise data lake environment and analytics engine.
- Hands on with AWS cloud technologies, lambda function development in java, performing treatment of apache parquet files for multidimensional model.

05/2013 to 02/2020

Information Technology Analyst: National Supply Company, Brazil

- Technical Coordinator of the Nucleus of Architecture and Innovation.
- Development of microservices based on Spring boot in Java and reusable visual components based on Angular.

Languages

English Portuguese

Courses

Big Data on AWS: Fast Lane BR **Architecting on AWS**: Fast Lane BR **Qlik Sense GeoAnalytics**: Toccato

Tecnologia

Qlik Sense Advanced Architecture:

Toccato Tecnologia

Introduction to Data Science: Data

Science Academy

Big Data Fundamentals: Data

Science Academy

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS Certified Developer Associate

OCE JPA - Oracle Certified Expert,
Java EE 6 Java Persistence API
Developer): Oracle

OCE EJB - Oracle Certified Expert,
Java EE 6 Enterprise JavaBeans
Developer Certified Expert: Oracle

SCWCD - Sun Certified Web Component Developer: Oracle

SCJP - Sun Certified Java Programmer: Oracle

IBM Certified Solution Designer – Object Oriented Analysis and Design, vUML 2: IBM

IBM Certified SOA Associate: IBM

- Conducting research and implantation of architecture java based on micro services, using spring framework and the concept of resources server's controlled by Oauth2.
- Responsible for the research and implantation of proposal of control of distributed transaction of the micro services, based on Spring Atomikos and Kafka.
- Work with the most common packages and frameworks such as like Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, JAX-RS, JSF with good experience in front-end technology Angular.
- Made archetypes maven contemplating the architectures defined for the Company.
- Carried out strategic planning of technological direction and I provided training for the development teams.
- Made study, and definition of flow and self-service BI tools.
- Coordinating the technical team and acting directly in the realization of data ingestion PoC with masking, structuring, and documentation of Hadoop environment, using framework's Spark, Hive, Pentaho.
- Production of panels with Qlik Sense.

10/2009 to 04/2013

Senior Software Engineer: CTIS, Brazil

- Integrating the development team that maintains web solutions for internal and external use.
- Work as a Senior Developer work with JSF, Struts, JSP, Hibernate, EJB, PL-SQL, Oracle.
- Implement enterprise application projects, directing requirements definition, development, validation, and ongoing maintenance activities.

Education

2014-2016

Master of Business Administration (MBA) : Strategic Management in Information Technology - FGV - Fundação Getulio Vargas

2007-2010

Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.): Information Technology - Universidade Católica de Brasília

Personal Projects

Edux Concursos (https://www.eduxconcurso.com.br)

• Helps students pass in public exams. Web platform based on Angular and spring boot microservices in Java, it also has a mobile application built on Ionic Framework.

Brazilian Election Analysis (https://github.com/wescleysrn/election-analysis)

Open data processing of Brazilian electoral campaign donations, using graph-based database Neo4J,
 Spring and Angular.

Code Challenge (https://github.com/wescleysrn/code-challenges-wescley)

• Project that centralizes diverse code challenge and learning in algorithms and data structure.

Resource Server Trigger (https://github.com/wescleysrn/disparador-rs)

• Design for triggering scheduled tasks in a distributed microservices ecosystem.

Hobbies

Run, Travel, Krav Mag Training, Photograph